Guide to the Meyer Schapiro Collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: Sound and video recordings, 1952-1990s
  - Subseries: VII.2: Audiocassettes and Audiotapes, 1952-1982
    - Modern painting since 1900 (Art History G4640y) -- Columbia University -- 1965 February - April
      - Lecture VIII
        - 1 sound tape reel, 59 minutes analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 507)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 59 minutes, analogue (Box 401)
      - Lecture IX
        - 1 sound tape reel, 57 minutes analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 508)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 57 minutes, analogue (Box 401)
      - Lecture XIV
        - 1 sound tape reel, 52 minutes analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 509)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 52 minutes, analogue (Box 401)
    - Carolingian manuscripts -- Columbia University, 1966 January 3
      (There is a hum on the tape, making it difficult to hear the lecture. Sound quality is poor)
      - 1 sound tape reel, 56 minutes analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 510)
      - 2 sound cassettes, 56 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
    - Guernica -- Harvard University, Carpenter Design Center -- 1966 December 15
      (Reels in Boxes 512 through 514 are duplicates of of the reel in Box 511. The lecture is complete. The voice is audible and clear but the sound level varies.)
      - 4 sound tape reels, 83 minutes analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 511-514)
      - 1 sound cassettes, 83 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
    - The unity of Picasso's art -- Brandeis University -- 1967 April 11
      (Columbia University's Rare Book & Manuscript Library is not in the possession of original sound tape reels. Sound quality is good. Film of the lecture was made by The Metroplican Museum of Art in association with Gittelman Film Associates in 1985)
      - 2 sound cassettes, 98 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 402)
    - Romanesque architectural sculpture -- Charles Eliot Norton lectures -- Harvard University -- 1967 February 8 - March 28
      (For consistency, lecture titles correspond to those in the posthumous publication Romanesque architectural sculpture: The Charles Eliot Norton lectures. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 2006. Lecture titles as they appeared in the Metropolitan Museum of Art's inventory: Lecture I: Rebirth of monumental sculpture in the West-disappearance and return; Lecture II: Field, figure and frame (1); Lecture III: Field, figure and frame (2); Lecture IV: Programs of imagery-theemes of action and themes of state; Lecture V: Programs of imagery-tradition, new reality and nature; Lecture VI: The human figure; Lecture VII: Romanesque animal imagery.)
      - Lecture I: the rebirth of monumental sculpture in the west: disappearance and rebirth, 1967 February 8
        - 1 sound tape reel, 72 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, mono (Box 515)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 72 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
      - Lecture II: field, figure, and frame, 1967 February 15
        - 1 sound tape reel, 63 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, mono (Box 516)
        - peb1 sound cassette, 63 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 402)
      - Lecture III: field, figure, and frame, 1967 March 8
        - 1 sound tape reel, 88 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, mono (Box 517)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 88 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
      - Lecture IV: programs of imagery (i), 1967 March 11
        - 1 sound tape reel, 79 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, mono (Box 518)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 79 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
      - Lecture V: programs of imagery (ii), 1967 March 15
        - 1 sound tape reel, 82 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, mono (Box 519)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 82 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
      - Lecture VI: the human figure, 1967 March 22
        - 1 sound tape reel, 91 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, mono (Box 520)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 91 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
      - Lecture VII: animal imagery in Romanesque sculpture, 1967 March
        - 1 sound tape reel, 82 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, mono (Box 521)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 82 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
    - On drawing from the figure -- New York Studio School of Drawing, Painting and Sculpture -- 1967 May 26
      - 1 sound tape reel, 110 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, mono (Box 522)
      - 5 sound cassettes, 110 minutes, analogue (Box 402)
    - Abstract painting (Art History G4641x) -- Columbia University -- 1967 October - December, 1968 January
      (All the lectures are complete except for lecture II where the second half of the lecture was not recorded, and lecture XII where the sound disappears. Sound quality of these lectures is mixed)
      - Lecture I: introduction, 1967 October 4
        - 1 sound tape reel, 70 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 523)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 70 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture II: meaning of "abstract" preconditions for Abstract painting, 1967 October 11
        - 1 sound tape reel, 50 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 524)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 50 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture III: Preconditions for Abstract painting continued and art preceding abstraction -- Annotated typescript and outlines, 1967 October 18
        - 1 sound tape reel, 42 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 525)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 42 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture IV: themes in art preceding abstraction (1870-1910), 1967 October 25
        - 1 sound tape reel, 94 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 526)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 94 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture V: role of photography and introduction to Cubism, 1967 November 1
        - 1 sound tape reel, 104 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 527)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 104 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture VI: Picasso before Cubism, the Fauves, 1967 November 8
        - 1 sound tape reel, 99 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 528)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 99 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture VII: Cubism, Picasso and Braque, 1967 November 15
        - 1 sound, 93 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 529)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 93 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture VIII: Cubism, 1967 November 22
        - 1 sound tape reel, 100 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 530)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 100 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture IX: developments from Cubism, simultaneity, and the concept of time in painting, 1967 November 29
        - 2 sound tape reels, 108 minutes each, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 531-532)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 108 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture X: development of Cubism: France and Italy, 1967 December 6
        - 2 sound tape reels, 103 minutes each, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 533-534)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 103 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture XI: Futurism, Russia, and Suprematism, 1967 December 13
        - 1 sound tape reel, 106 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 535)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 106 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture XII: Suprematism and German Expressionism, 1967 December 20
        - 1 sound tape reel, 102 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 536)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 102 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture XIII: Kandinsky and Mondrian, 1968 January 10
        - 2 sound tape reels, 136 minutes each, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 537-538)
        - 3 sound cassettes, 136 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture XIV: developments from Cubism in America, 1968 January 17
        - 2 sound tape reels, 109 minutes each, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 539-540)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 109 minutes, analogue (Box 403)
      - Lecture XV: American Abstract art -- Annotated typescript, 1968 January 24
        - 2 sound tape reels, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 541-542)
    - Abstract art -- Slade Lectures in the Fine Arts -- Oxford University -- 1968 Spring
      (Sound quality for this entire series is poor. Only lectures III, VI, and VII are complete. The beginnings and endings are cut off on lectures I and II. The endings are cut off on lectures VI through VI.)
      - Lecture I: modern Abstract art: its continuity with preceding realistic art, 1968 May 3
        - 1 sound tape reel, 7 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second (Box 543)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 7 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 404)
      - Lecture II: Cubism (i), 1968 May 8
        (Annotations indicate that Lecture I is included in this reel even though the Metropolitan Museum of Art inventory does not)
        - 1 sound tape reel, 130 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 544)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 67 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture III: Cubism (ii), 1968 May 15
        - 1 sound tape reel, 130 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 544)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 63 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture IV: Cubism and science, 1968 May 22
        - 1 sound tape reel, 114 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 545)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 76 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture V: Cubism and technology, 1968 May 22
        - 1 sound tape reel, 114 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track) (Box 545)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 38 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture VI: Abstract painting: Malevich and Mondrian, 1968 May 24
        - 1 sound tape reel, 34 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second (Box 546)
        - 1 sound tape reel, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 547)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 34 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture VII: Abstract painting: Kandinsky, 1968 May
        - 1 sound tape reel, 62 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second (Box 548)
        - 1 sound, analogue, 9.5centimeters per second (Box 549)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 62 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture VIII: Abstract painting in America: Pollock, Rothko, and others, 1968 May 29
        - 1 sound tape reel, 74 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second (Box 550)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 74 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
    - Philosophy and worldview in painting -- Oxford University -- 1968 June 4
      - 2 sound tape reels, 129 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second (Box 551-552)
      - 2 sound cassettes, 219 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
    - Insular manuscript art -- Franklin Jasper Walls lectures -- Pierpont Morgan library -- 1968 March
      (Schapiro referred to these lectures as "Hiberno-Saxon manuscripts," the title reflects that used in Series III, Subseries: III.3: Lectures, Sub-Subseries: III.3.4: 1960s)
      - Lecture I: frame, field, and figure, 1968 March 4
        - 1 sound tape reel, 273 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 553)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 70 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture II: the carpet page and the giant initial, 1968 March 11
        - 1 sound tape reel, 273 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 553)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 84 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture III: image and ornament, 1968 March 18
        - 1 sound tape reel, 273 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 553)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 97 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture IV: the models and their transformation (i), 1968 March 20
        - 1 sound tape reel, 273 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 554)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 88 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture V: the models and their transformation (ii), 1968 March 25
        - 1 sound tape reel, 273 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 554)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 75 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
      - Lecture VI: the religious and secular grounds of Hiberno-Saxon art, 1968 March 27
        - 1 sound tape reel, 273 minutes, analogue, 19 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 554)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 110 minutes, analogue (Box 404)
    - Baudelaire between the imaginary and the real -- Queens College (New York, N.Y.) -- 1969 April 22
      - 1 sound tape reel, 86 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 555)
      - 1 sound cassettes, 86 minutes, analogue (Box 405)
    - Beatus manuscripts of the apocalypse -- New York Studio School of Drawing, Painting and Sculpture, 1969 May 2
      - 1 sound tape reel, 120 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 556)
      - 4 sound cassettes, 120 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 405)
        (Accompanied by administrative notes by Lillian Milgram Schapiro)
    - The present state of art history -- Queens College (New York, N.Y.) -- Annotated outlines, transcript, and notes, 1969 June 5
      - 1 sound tape reel, 98 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 557)
      - 2 sound cassettes, 98 minutes, analogue (Box 405)
    - E.A. (Elias Avery) Lowe memorial -- Institute for Advanced Study (Princeton, N.J.) -- 1969 October 15
      - 1 sound tape reel, 72 minutes, analogue (Box 558)
      - 2 sound cassettes, 72 minutes, analogue (Box 405)
    - Theory and methods of art history (Art History G6001x) -- Columbia University -- 1969 October - 1970 January
      (All lectures are complete except for the beginning of lecture I, and the endings of lectures V and VII. The sound quality of the series is poor. There is a hiss on all the recordings, with the voice audible but not good. Questions from the audience are difficult to hear, and sometimes inaudible.)
      - Lecture I, 1969 October 1
        - 1 sound tape reel, 41 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 559)
        - 1 sound cassettes, 41 minutes, analogue (Box 405)
      - Lecture II, 1969 October 8
        - 1 sound tape reel, 102 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 560)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 102 minutes, analogue (Box 405)
      - Lecture III, 1969 October 22
        - 1 sound tape reel, 109 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 561)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 109 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 405)
      - Lecture IV, 1969 October 29
        - 1 sound tape reel, 103 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 562)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 103 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture V, 1969 November 5
        - 1 sound tape reel, 107 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 563)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 107 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture VI, 1969 November 12
        - 1 sound tape reel, 105 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 564)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 105 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture VII, 1969 November 19
        - 1 sound tape reel, 102 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 565)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 102 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture VIII, 1969 November 26
        - 1 sound tape reel, 113 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 566)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 113 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture IX, 1969 December 3
        - 1 sound tape reel, 111 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 567)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 111 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture X, 1969 December 10
        - 1 sound tape reel, 111 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 568)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 111 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture XI, 1969 December 17
        - 1 sound tape reel, 110 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 569)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 110 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture XII, 1970 January 7
        - 1 sound tape reel, 114 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 570)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 114 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
      - Lecture XIII, 1970 January 14
        - 1 sound tape reel, 147 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 571)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 147 minutes, analogue (Box 406)
    - Three texts by Lichtenberg, Diderot and Galiani -- New York Studio School of Drawing, Painting and Sculpture -- 1970 April 10
      - 3 sound cassettes, 108 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 407)
    - Early Christian painting (Art History G4320x) -- Columbia University -- 1970 Fall
      (The sound quality of these lectures is mixed. The beginnings of lectures I-IV, VI, VIII, and XII are cut off. The sound is good on lectures IV-VIII, XI, and XIII. On other lectures the recordings have static and hum sounds, audience noise, and the professor is sometimes off microphone. Annotations indicate the title as "Early Christian art," but Columbia University class bulletins list the course as Early Christian painting)
      - Lecture I, 1970 September 30
        - 1 sound tape reel, 102 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 572)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 102 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture II, 1970 October 7
        - 1 sound tape reel, 102 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 573)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 102 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture III, 1970 October 14
        - 1 sound tape reel, 98 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 574)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 98 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture IV, 1970 October 21
        - 1 sound tape reel, 113 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 575)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 113 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture V, 1970 October 28
        - 1 sound tape reel, 102 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 576)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 102 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture VI, 1970 November 4
        - 1 sound tape reel, 112 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 577)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 112 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture VII, 1970 November 11
        - 1 sound tape reel, 102 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 578)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 112 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture VIII, 1970 November 18
        - 1 sound tape reel, 108 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 579)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 108 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture IX, 1970 November 25
        - 1 sound tape reel, 104 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 580)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 104 minutes, analogue (Box 407)
      - Lecture X, 1970 December 2
        - 1 sound tape reel, 107 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 581)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 107 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
      - Lecture XI, 1970 December 9
        - 1 sound tape reel, 104 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 582)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 104 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
      - Lecture XII, 1970 December 16
        - 1 sound tape reel, 100 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 583)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 100 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
      - Lecture XIII, 1971 January 6
        - 1 sound tape reel, 116 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 584)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 116 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
    - Men with ideas: Alexander, Daedalus, Icarus: legends of the invention of flying -- Carnegie Institute of Technology -- 1971 January 27
      (The original audiotape was torn and needed to be repaired before the cassette copy was recorded. The lecture is complete with good sound. The voice is clear and audible.)
      - 1 sound tape reel, 87 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 585)
      - 1 sound cassettes, 87 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
    - Ornament and painting -- New York Studio School of Drawing, Painting and Sculpture -- 1971 April 23
      (The sound quality is poor, with echoes and muffling of the voice.)
      - 1 sound tape reel, 170 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second, 2 track (Box 586)
      - 2 sound cassettes, 170 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
    - Mondrian's forms and their relation to preceding styles of representation -- Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum -- 1971 October 9
      (The lecture is complete, but the sound quality is mixed. The voice is clear and audible, but the sound level varies. There is audience noise and the professor taps on the podium and is occasionally off microphone.)
      - 1 sound tape reel, 38 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 587)
      - 1 sound cassette, 38 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 408)
    - Graphic analysis of structure -- University of Virginia -- 1972 April 11
      (The lecture is complete, but the sound quality is poor. The voice is high-pitched, and there is audience noise and varied sound levels.)
      - 1 sound tape reel, 53 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 588)
      - 1 sound cassettes, 53 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
    - An experiment with forms in art -- Columbia University -- 1973 April 2
      (The lecture is complete, but the sound quality is poor. There is a hiss on the recording, and an echo effect.)
      - 1 sound tape reel, 66 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 589)
      - 1 sound cassettes, 66 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
    - The south tower of the cathedral of Chartres -- Columbia University. School of Architecture -- 1973 October 3
      (The lecture is complete with voice audible. The quality of the sound is mixed, with audience noise, echo sound, and the professor is occasionally off microphone)
      - 1 sound tape reel, 83 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 590)
      - 1 sound cassettes, 83 minutes, analogue (Box 408)
    - The use of the Old Testament in the art of the middle ages -- Jewish Museum (New York, N.Y.) -- 1973 October 22
      (All three sound tape reels are incomplete and do not have the end of the lecture recorded. The sound quality is poor with a great deal of audience noise, although the voice itself is clear.)
      - 3 sound tape reels, 129 minutes each, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 591-593)
      - 4 sound cassettes, 129 minutes, analogue (Box 409)
    - The unity of Picasso's art -- Albright-Knox Art Gallery -- 1973 December 5
      (The lecture is complete with good sound quality, the voice is clear and audible. Film of this lecture was made in 1985 by The Metropolitan Museum and Gittelman Film Associates)
      - 2 sound cassettes, 94 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 409)
    - Theories and methods of investigation of art (Art History G6001x) -- Columbia University, 1974 Fall
      (Lectures I and II were not recorded. All the recorded lectures are complete. The sound quality of this series is mixed. In most recordings the voice is clear and audible, but there is a lot of audience noise and some sounds from a construction site nearby are noticeable on lectures III through VI. The sound is very poor for lectures IV and XI.)
      - Lecture III, 1974 October 2
        - 1 sound tape reel, 108 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 594)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 108 minutes, analogue (Box 409)
      - Lecture IV, 1974 October 9
        - 1 sound tape reel, 106 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 595)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 106 minutes, analogue (Box 409)
      - Lecture V, 1974 October 16
        - 1 sound tape reel, 107 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 596)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 107 minutes, analogue, mono (Box 409)
      - Lecture VI, 1974 October 23
        - 1 sound tape reel, 104 minutes, analogue, 9.5 centimeters per second (Box 597)
        - 2 sound cassettes, 104 minutes, analogue (Box 409)
      - Lecture VII, 1974 October 30